Geoffrey Bergeret French Nationality 28 years old

Infrastructure Engineer

« Single Responsibility Principle »

+44 7871 334653 job@gbergeret.com www.gbergeret.org

Profile

By experience, I acquired lots of skills in several area like: *Software*, *System*, *Network* or *DevOps* Culture. Now my goal is to focus on the DevOps way: "*Develop your infrastructure as code and automate everything to make it smarter*".

Work Experience

Infrastructure Engineer at Fluidly – 01/2019 to now

- Migrate from Heroku to Google Cloud Platform to host our infrastructure
- Support our mono-environment (no staging, no QA but only 1 environment production)
- Improve CI/CD speed to reduce time to market to less than a day
- Restructured Terraform projects integrate them with the CI/CD pipeline
- Integrate Kapitan and Helm with Terraform projects to manage Kubernetes provisioning
- Develop DevSecOps culture to the whole engineering team

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 10/2017 to 01/2019

- Initiated GitOps principales from Infrastructure as Code (with Peer Review).
- Implement Jenkins Pipeline integration with terraform to run terraform from Jenkins.
- Restructured Terraform projects integrate them with the CI/CD pipeline.
- Integrate Ansible with our Terraform projects to manage OS provisioning.
- Worked on AWS accounts segregation with AWS Organisation (workload segregation).
- Deployed and maintain transit VPC (with datapath.io solution) cross regions and VPCs.

DevOps Engineer at Drivetribe – 11/2016 to 10/2017

- Infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (GitOps).
- Move platform to docker infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Refactoring environments to be easy to run, update and dispose (ga, staging, prod).
- Work around failure points and scalability to be online as much as possible..
- Improve, speed up and stabilise the releasing process.

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 04/2016 to 11/2016

- Move to infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (all in git).
- Move platform to micro-services infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Work around failure points to be as much as possible always online.

System and DevOps Engineer at Contentment – 10/2015 to 03/2016

Education & Training

2015: Master of Science in Computer and Network Engineering (1st class) at ESIPE

Languages Skills

French —> Native

English -> Fluent (living in UK from 2015)

Technical Skills

DevOps: Kubernetes, terraform, test-kitchen, GitOps, CI/CD (Jenkins, CircleCI)

System: Linux, Bash, Ansible, Python, Docker

Infrastructure: AWS, GCP, VPN, Kubernetes, Firewall (pfsense, ipables)
Networking: Routing (OSPF, BGP), VRRP, OpenVPN, DHCP, DNS
Database: MERISE, ORM, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
Software Development: UML, Java, C/C++, Jekyll (Liquid), Git

Management Skills

Project Management Independent

Team organisation Facilitate meeting

Conduct training Seminar facilitator

Hobbies

Board Games Economy/Finance Cooking
Jogging/Fitness

Traveling Motorcycle